

### **Manoj Kumar**

• Home: 245301, Hapur, Uttar Pradesh, India

**Email:** manojkumar4068@gmail.com **Phone:** (+91) 8800699499

**○ Whatsapp Messenger:** +918800699499

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/manoj-kumar-452649b1

#### **ABOUT ME**

Maintenance manager with 8 years proven background in pharmaceutical industry. Experience in Managing a team of 20 people including Operator, technician, helper and casual worker. Have traveled extensively for project related work making me an excellent candidate for the position I am seeking.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 01/2021 – Current ]

#### **Maintenance Manager**

Pharmanova SARL Ltd pharmanovagh.com

**Citv:** Grand bassam Country: Côte d'Ivoire

Email address: info@pharmanovagh.com

**Business or sector:** Manufacturing

**Job Description** 

- 1. Operation and preventive break down maintenance of Tablet processing machine as well as utilities and HVAC system.
- 2. Assessing programmers with troubleshooting, upgrading as well as installation of SCADA, PLC and HDMI hardware for proper function of PLC machine.
- 3. Preparation of Documents (SOP, URS,DQ,IQ,OQ) and review of existing SOP for new
- 4. Coordinating with other Departments to complete the Validation/Calibration of Equipment on time.
- 5. Collection of quotation from different vendors and preparing purchase Order to keep critical inventory.
- 6. Preparation of Annual budget for purchasing machine spare, consumable item and AMC of machines.
- 7. Maintains a safe and clean working environment by enforcing procedures, rule and regulations.

# [ 04/2018 - 07/2020 ] **Maintenance Engineer**

#### Alkem laboratories Itd

City: Sikkim Country: India **Job Description** 

- 1. Operation and maintenance of utility equipment (Air compressor, Chiller cooling tower, pump, Air dryer).
- 2. Operation and preventive Breakdown maintenance of high speed injectible BFS machine(Rommelag 360,321) and packing machine (HPHV,Autoclave,Sterlizer,high cart, Flow wrap) machine.
- 3. Ensured availability of engineering person in rotating shift to maximize production.
- 4. Coordinatend with vendor to successfully install new equipment related to engineering and production area.

# [ 03/2016 - 03/2018 ] **Project Engineer**

#### Molsieve Designs Itd

City: Noida Country: India **Job Description** 

- 1. Completed all work regarding Erection and commissioning of PSA Gas(Nitrogen, Hydrogen, Gas Dryer)plant project.
- 2. PLC programming and SCADA designing for on going project.
- 3. Overseen development of detailed design drawing including instrument plan &detailed wiring.
- 4. Trouble shooting of control panel and instruments.
- 5. Supervised of installation and commissioning of field instrument like pressure sensor, RTD sensor, alarms, transducers, control valves and differently pressure switch.

## [ 12/2013 - 03/2016 ] **Maintenance Engineer**

#### Higlance laboratories Itd

City: Noida Country: India **Job Description** 

- 1. Trouble shooting of production Machine ie. Tablet Compression, Tablet Coating, Packing line And Granulation.
- 2. Operation and Maintenance of utility equipment(Air Compressor, Water Chiller, Cooling tower, Diesel Generator) Equipment.
- 3. Maintained daily record of consumption of Steam, Water and Electricity.
- 4. Maintained daily log Book for Engg. Equipment and HVAC System.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

[2009 - 2014]

### **B.**Tech in Electronics and Telecommunications Engineering

Address: Uttarpradesh, India

## $[\,2006\,-\,2010\,]$ Diploma in Electronics Engineering

Address: Uttarpradesh, India

[ 01/2023 – Current ]

#### **Post graduate Certificate in Industrial Safety**

**IGNOU** 

## [ 23/05/2020 ] Project Management Essentials Certified

## $[\,22/05/2020\,]$ Lean Six Sigma White Belt

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Hindi

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING B1 READING B2 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1**